One of the reasons that we did GitHub
pages first as a deployment option is
because this option actually relies on
GitHub to deploy. Um so this option is
called forcell and um they uh built a
nice JavaScript framework called Nex.js
and it's a wonderful framework for
building pages and um you can learn
about that in the future but for now
we're just going to deploy our normal
dice roller app just like we did last
time. And to do that, um, you'll want to
sign up for an account. So, you'll click
sign up, and I'm going to click that I
am working on personal projects. Um,
and then I'm going to click continue.
And then it says, let's create your
account. And I'm going to continue with
GitHub. And I'm going to continue with
my account. What you're doing is you're
authorizing it to let you log in using
GitHub.
And so it wants to one verify your
identity, two um we're going to let
Verscell know what they can access from
our GitHub and three we're going to let
it act on our behalf. Um but the main
resources it's going to use is it's
going to verify our email address to
verify that we are who we say we are. So
I'm going to authorize that.
And now we are on Versel. Um and we will
need to enter our phone number to verify
our login. And I'm going to stop the
recording for that.
Okay, as soon as you've entered the code
that they text you, you will be brought
to this location. So, we want to bring
in a GitHub repository. Um, to do that,
you'll have to install it. Install the
GitHub application here. So, what you'll
do is you'll click install.
And it says which user wants to
authorize for cell. And so, I'm going to
go as the user I was with. If you only
have one GitHub account, that's probably
what you'll get. All right. Now it wants
to know which GitHub wants to know which
repositories you want for cell to
access. Um you could do all repositories
and it would be able to access all of
them read only. Um but I'm going to do
only select repositories because I only
want it to access a specific repository
or maybe a couple of specific
repositories. In this case I want it to
access dice roller or dice roller. I
want it to be able to read and write it.
Um, and now I'm going to click install.
Once I've clicked install, it now has
access to dice roller and I can click
import. Okay, so you're going to be
asked to create a new project. I'm going
to name leave my default as dice roller.
If you were deploying like an Angular
project or React app or like there's a
whole bunch of things that you could be
trying to deploy, um, you could put one
of those, but I'm just going to leave it
as other because we aren't using a
framework. We're just writing normal
vanilla JavaScript. So, we're going to
leave it as other. Um, then it says,
what directory do you want to deploy
from? If you remember, our index.html
file is in our root directory. So, we're
going to go ahead and leave that. And
we're going to click deploy.
And this is going to take a minute to
deploy or a couple seconds actually. So,
the deploying is cued. It started to 3
seconds for And it's done. Okay. So,
we're going to continue to the
dashboard. And you can see we have a
preview of our live running site. And
I'm going to do a hard refresh on this
page.
And it says it's pulling from our main
branch. Some of you may see a problem
with that. So if I open up the domain
and I roll the dice, if you had merged
your code with the main branch, this
would have been a perfectly deployed
piece of code. Sometimes you want to
deploy from a different branch. In my
case, I want to deploy from the deploy
branch. This is just the starter code
with no JavaScript written in it. So to
change that, you're going to come back
here. You're going to click on settings.
You're going to click on environments.
And here where it says production um
that code is pulling from the main
branch. We don't want it to pull from
the main branch. We want to pull it from
the deploy branch. So we're going to
click on this and we're going to change
the name from main to deploy.
Then we're going to hit save.
So it says each commit pushed to the
deploy branch will create a production
deployment.
Now you can come over here to overview.
Here you can see that the source is
main. If we do a control shift R or
command shift R to hard refresh the
page, that means don't pull from cache.
Um, you can see right now it still says
the source is main. But if you look down
here, it says to update your production
deployment, push to the deploy branch.
Meaning, if we want this to change,
because right now, if we click this
link, click roll the dice, nothing's
happening. If we want it to change, we
have to make a change to our deploy
branch. This used to say main and now it
says deploy because we've switched which
branch it's watching.
So to show you the real power of this,
let's come over here and let's go to our
dice roller and instead of being on
main, switch to your deploy branch or
whatever you call your branch. And then
I'm going to edit this dice roller right
here. And I'm just going to add a new
line and commit my changes. And I'm
going to say um redeploying with new
read me.
And we're going to commit directly to
the deploy branch. So we commit that
and now
um our GitHub pages is redeploying. You
can see it right there. Um but if we
come over here
um and we do a hard refresh on this
page, you can see it takes a minute and
it says now the source is deploy. Oops,
didn't mean to click that. Now the
source is deploy and it redeployed with
the new readme. So that means all of my
changes that I just made to my code are
now live. So if I click on this link,
you can see that my dice are rolling. I
pulled code from the correct branch. I
can freeze the dice. And so the nice
thing about Verscell is that as you push
changes to your code branch, Verscell
will redeploy it for you. And so that is
how you deploy on Versel. And you can
see from the URL, it's
https-roller-neon.vercell
app. And if we come over and reload this
page,
um,
sorry, if we reload this page, you can
see that the domain
is dice- roller-neon.cell.app.
And your app is live. Anyone can just
this